

Paul Beaton

Senior Application Developer

Phone: 813-528-3068

GitHub: github.com/pjbeaton

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/pauljbeaton/

Email: pjbeaton@hotmail.com

15+ year consultant developing software solutions using the Microsoft Stack. Roles range from developer, team lead, architect, business analyst, project manager, program manager and practice lead. Specialist in mobile application development. Focused on implementing best practices to ensure software architecture is flexible, testable and maintainable. Passionate about learning new and improved ways to solve problems. Currently focused on gaining more experience with front-end javascript frameworks (i.e. React).

Windows Phone apps have surpassed the 1,000,000 download mark.

EXPERIENCE

Sogeti

May 2011 - Present (5 years 10 months)

Mgr. IT Consultant / Digital Transformation Practice Lead

Senior Microsoft Developer/Team Lead using .NET. Main focus on creating web and mobile applications to delight the end-user. Project experience with MVC, Web API, HTML5, XAML, WCF and Scrum. Internal project experience using React and Redux. Passion in creating applications to engage the user with an outstanding experience.

Mentor to many mid to beginner level developers. Regular speaker at Lunch and Learn meetings. Active local development community member. Technical lead on many different pursuits leading to several engagements. Developed and presented training courses on Windows Phone and Windows 8 application development within Sogeti.

JEWL Solutions

January 2011 - December 2011 (1 year)

.NET Web Application Developer

Developed and managed project plans, issues log and status updates. Developed multiple web application user interfaces using C#.NET, HTML 5, CSS3, Javascript and ASP.NET within Visual Studio 2010 connecting to SQL Server utilizing the Agile development methodology and test driven development. Developed web application using MVC3 framework.

IBM Global Services

January 2003 - January 2009 (6 years 1 month)

IT Project/Program Manager 2004

- Program Manager led team of 4 project managers for Infrastructure projects
- Project Manager led multiple Infrastructure project teams
- Billing Manager led team of 5 people managing client billing for large client
- Security Analyst documented application security for multiple global applications
- Financial Analyst documented and analyzed large client financials

IBM

January 1999 - January 2003 (4 years 1 month)

Web Application Programmer/Lead

Excelled in web application programming. Led team of 5 web developers to implement a product ordering system for a large automotive company. The technologies used in completing this application included Visual InterDev, ASP, COM+, HTML/DHTML, XML, CSS, Crystal Reports, Javascript and communication with DB2 stored procedures. Also produced several common APIs which were used by the entire development team for faster development time. While working on an inventory ordering system for a major automotive company, developed multiple user screens using Visual InterDev, ASP, COM+, HTML/DHTML, XML, CSS, Crystal Reports, Javascript and communication with DB2 stored procedures. Worked with fellow team members to implement a web enabled Project Information Collection Repository using Visual InterDev, server side VB script, client side Java Script, and SQL server.

Languages: C#, Visual Basic, Javascript, HTML and CSS

Databases: SQL Server, Oracle and DB2

Patterns: MVC, MVVM, MVP, Dependency Injection

Methodologies: Scrum and Waterfall ORM: Entity Framework and NPoco

Technologies: Web (ASP.Net MVC and Node.js), Mobile (Windows Phone), Cloud (Azure), Web Services (Web API)

Testing: Unit Testing, TDD, Fakes and Stubs

Client Side Frameworks: React and Redux (internally)

CLIENT PROJECTS

ACG - Custom Web-Based CRM Tool

March 2015 - current

- Lead developer on enhancement to enable client to offer auto loans to their customers. Project used C#, MVC, Web API, NPoco, JSON, HTML, JavaScript, CSS and unit testing.
- Created many administration screens to enable configuration for new system.
- Application configuration specialist for data center migration moving the CRM tool supporting 13 Million customers.
 Responsibilities included configuration and testing of application on roughly 50 servers supporting 4 environments.

Technologies used: C#, MVC, Web API, JSON, HTML, JavaScript, Visual Basic, WebForms and XML

ACG - Insurance Web Application

December 2014 - January 2015

Major contributor in upgrading current functionality for consumers and insurance agents

Technologies Used: Visual Basic, WCF, WebForms, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery and XML

Arizona Corporation Commission - MVC Web Application

August 2014 - December 2014

- Lead developer re-writing existing website to MVC5.
- Application required integration with existing Progress database.
- System was designed with data access layer, business layer and the MVC pattern.

Technologies Used: C#, MVC, HTML5, JavaScript and jQuery

TECO - Windows 8 Applications

November 2013 - March 2014

- Lead developer responsible for creating 2 Windows 8 modern applications.
- Led delivery, solution design, user interface and user experience designs.
- Created mobile strategy using internal templates and integrating TECO specific pieces

Technologies Used: C#, XAML, MVVM and SQLite

Chick-Fil-A - Windows Phone 8 Application

October 2013 - November 2013

- Designed, developed and delivered Windows Phone 8 application.
- Responsible for solution architecture, user interface and user experience.
- Application allowed employees to look up nearby restaurants, find key information on each location and check in to that location
- Along with delivery of the project, also led delivery of coding standards and code reviews

Technologies used: C#, XAML, MVVM and SQLite

Burger King - Mobile Web Site

August 2013 - September 2013

- Lead developer on HTML5 mobile site designed to appear like a native iPhone app
- Second phase was to convert the website to a mobile app for all major platforms using Cordova

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ¡Query, Angular JS, Bootstrap and Cordova

Bloomin' Brands - Dashboard Support Tool for POS Data Transfer Process

July 2013 - September 2013

- MVC web application with dashboard and admin screen
- Data Access, service and presentation layer used to separate concerns using dependency injection to allow for unit testing
- · Oracle stored procedures used for data access

Technologies used: C#, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ASP.net MVP, Oracle and SQL Developer

Florida Power and Light - Windows 8 Application POC

May 2013 to June 2013

Windows 8 POC utilizing C#, XAML, MVVM and SQLite created using Visual Studio 2012 using Expression Blend and TFS Online.

Home Shopping Network - Real-time inventory web application

February 2013 - April 2013

- Rest web service developer using Web API for Real-Time inventory reporting application
- Implemented caching on the server to enable fast response
- Automated unit testing implemented to ensure accuracy of Web API data
- Created Oracle stored procedures for data access

Sogeti Internal Projects

May 2011 - Current

- Sogeti Florida weekly sales report tool lead developer/architect in writing the website using React/Redux, Web API and SQL Azure all hosted on Azure.
- Sogeti Battlecards app on Windows 8 lead developer/architect in writing the Sogeti Battlecard app for Windows 8.
- Sogeti Hub app on Windows Phone lead developer in re-writing the Sogeti hub app to pull data from a secure JSON feed instead of hard-coding the information within the app.
- Sogeti Battlecards app on Windows Phone lead developer on the redesign of the Windows Phone 7 app and conversion to Windows Phone 8.
- Sogeti recruiting app on Windows 8 assisted in the design and implementation of the Windows 8 recruiting app used to provide Sogeti information to prospective students. This application has been used as a showcase app for Sogeti at college campuses.
- Windows Phone Development Training presented 2 sessions (data access and the Pivot control vs. the Panorama control).
- Windows 8 Training presented 3 sessions (data access, Windows 8 controls and the Windows Store process)
- In addition to the internal projects, Paul has published 6 Windows Phone applications reaching over 1M downloads while maintaining a high review rating and has also published a Windows 8 application; which has been showcased to Microsoft.

EDUCATION

Central Michigan University

BS, Computer Science

1994 - 1999